Guide to the Robert Grenier Papers
Department of Special Collections
Robert Grenier papers
1941-1999
M1082
Grenier, Robert 1941-
54 linear feet
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Includes notebooks, 1968-1989; correspondence, 1948-1999; manuscripts by others, 1950-1999; Grenier's youth, 1941-1965; lectures, 1981-1998; critical writings, 1960-1998; poetry manuscripts, 1966-1998; book manuscripts, 1967-1997; files on works, 1971-1997; journal articles, 1959-1998; color slides (1,285) of "Rhymms" project; and signed copies of published works, 1967-1998.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1999. Accession 1999-174
Scope and Content of Collection
Includes notebooks, 1968-1994; correspondence, 1948-1999; manuscripts by others, 1950-1999; Grenier's youth, 1941-1965; lectures, 1981-1998; critical writings, 1960-1998; poetry manuscripts, 1966-1998; book manuscripts, 1967-1997; histories of making/production of five Grenier works, 1971-1997; journal articles, 1959-1998; color slides (1,285) of "rhymms" project; signed copies of published works, 1967-1998; "rhymms" teaching materials, 1968-1992; and audiotapes of poets reading their works from Grenier's collection, 1958-1974.
This electronic finding aid has been derived from a paper finding aid by Robert Grenier. All stylistic errors in this finding aid result from the inability of encoding to accurately represent the structure of Robert Grenier's original finding aid and are not the work of the author.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
American literature--20th century.
Collection Contents
- Series I. Robert Grenier Notebooks 1968 Oct - 1994 June
  Scope and Contents Note
  RG's Notebooks date from 1968 through 1994 and are divided into two subseries. Subseries 1 is a listing of RG's Notebooks from 1968-1989 and consists of 87 individual notebooks. Subseries 2 is a supplementary inventory of RG Notebooks dating from 1989-1994 (see Series I, Subseries 2 for a more detailed description). In general the Notebooks are identified by label (to the best of RG's ability, by internal references and occasional explicit dates) by date of composition, period of RG's writing and place of composition (e.g. "September 1972, Sentences period, Franconia, NH"). Notebooks are of varying sizes, with those of 150 sheets, 5 1/2" by 9 1/2" being most common. Notebooks are commonly filled on both sides of the sheets and for the most part contain RG's poems and occasional critical writings. There are some drawings and collaborative ventures by various hands (e.g. Anselm Hollo, John Bátki). The Notebooks listed in Subseries 1 are usually written in ink of one color those listed in Subseries 2 are commonly written in green, blue, black and red ink.
  - Subseries 1. RG Notebooks from Preliminary Inventory
    - A. October 1968 - September 1972, (26 notebooks) (Box 001)
    - B. September 1972 - October 1977, (31 notebooks) (Box 002)
    - C. December 1977 - March 1989, (30 notebooks) (Box 003)
  - Subseries 2. RG Notebooks from Supplementary Inventory1989 Sept - 1994 June
    The first of ten (5 1/2" by 8 1/2") notebooks from RG's ongoing color holograph drawing poem project, "rhymms", dated/chronologized and counted (by pages of text ("pp."))
    - A. Notebook 1 September 1989 - January 1990 (Box 030)
      Written in Berkeley, northern Minnesota & Bolinas, CA (RG moved to Bolinas in September 1989), containing poems in Minnesota (0 Books, 1991, see Preliminary Inventory, section XII.O.) & RG's first color drawing poems (155 pp. total)
    - B. Notebook 2 February 1990 - August 1990 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas (211 pp. total)
    - C. Notebook 3 September 1990 - January 1991 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas (131 pp. total)
    - D. Notebook 4 February 1991 - June 1991 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas, containing title image reproduced on green r h y m m s box cover & red tracing of RG's right hand designed for inside r h y m m s box back cover & other poems (178 pp. total)
    - E. Notebook 5 July 1991 - March 1992 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas (198 pp. total)
    - F. Notebook 6 April 1992 - September 1992 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas (148 pp. total)
    - G. Notebook 7 October 1992 - February 1993 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas (112 pp. total)
    - H. Notebook 8 March 1993 - July 1993 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas, containing "BJELDANES SERIES" (see Preliminary Inventory, sections VI.C.16. & X.BC.) & other poems (217 pp. total)
    - I. Notebook 9 August 1993 - January 1994 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas (229 pp. total)
    - J. Notebook 10 February 1994 - June 1994 (Box 030)
      Written in Bolinas, containing poems in :that:, No. 24 (August 1994) (see Preliminary Inventory, section VIII.W.) & other poems (143 pp. total)
- Series II. Literary Correspondence/Family Correspondence 1948 - 1999, RG alphabetized by author, dated/chronologized and counted (by letters & postcards) in folders. 4½ boxes.
  - Literary Correspondence
    - ADNAN, ETEL, - 7 letters and 2 postcards 1994 - 1999 - print-out of EA's "To Write in a Foreign Language" (Box 004)
    - ALFRED, WILLIAM, - 1 letter 1977 June 8 (Box 004)
    - ANDREWS, BRUCE, - 10 letters, 3 postcards 1977 - 1989 - 3 letters, RG to BA (xeroxes) 1987 (Box 004)
    - BATKI, JOHN, - approx. 76 letters and 2 postcards 1978 - 1998 - various mss. - various drawings and collages (Box 005)
    - BECKETT, TOM, - 11 letters and 3 postcards 1981 - 1988 - 1 letter RG to TB (xerox) 1986 Nov 24 (Box 004)
    - BELTRAMETTI, FRANCO, - 2 letters and 1 postcard 1991 - 1992 (Box 004)
    - BENSON, STEVE, - 3 letters and 1 postcard 1984 - 1996 (Box 004)
    - BERNSTEIN, CHARLES, - 23 letters and 15 postcards 1977 - 1996 - 3 letters RG to CB 1984 - 1988 (Box 004)
    - BIELEFELDT, CARL, - 2 letters 1962 - 3 letters to Marie Rexroth 1962 - 1968 (Box 004)
    - BOTSTEIN, LEON, - 1 letter 1977 (Box 004)
    - BROMIGE, DAVID, - 11 letters and 5 postcards 1982 - 1995 - 1 letter, RG to DB (xerox) 1984 (Box 004)
    - BYRD, DON, - 2 letters and 2 postcards 1985 - 1995 (Box 004)
    - CAIRNIE, GORDON, - 1 postcard 1970 (Box 004)
    - CODRESCU, ANDREI, - 1 letter 1987 (Box 004)
    - COOLIDGE, CLARK, - 9 letters and 1 postcard 1971 - 1977 (Box 004)
    - COLLOM, JACK, - 1 letter and 3 postcards 1992 - 1994 (Box 004)
    - CREELEY, ROBERT, - 46 letters and 40 postcards 1962 - 1998 (Box 004)
    - DALEY, JOHN, - 4 letters and 8 postcards 1982 - 1997 (Box 004)
    - DAVIDSON, MICHAEL, - 2 letters and 2 postcards 1986 - 1995 (Box 004)
    - DIGNAZIO, STEPHEN, - 3 letters and 4 postcards 1993 - 1996 (Box 004)
    - DORN, EDWARD, - 1 letter 1971 (Box 004)
    - DRUCKER, JOHANNA, - 2 letters 1980 - 1988 (Box 004)
    - EIGNER, LARRY, - 4 letters and 5 postcards 1976 - 1978 (Box 004)
    - FATTAL, SIMONE, - 2 letters and 7 postcards 1997 - 1998 (Box 004)
    - FAVILLE, CURTIS, - 6 letters and 2 postcards 1970 - 1985 (Box 004)
    - FISCHER, NORMAN, - 2 letters 1977 (Box 004)
    - FRUMKIN, KATHLEEN, - 2 postcards 1987 - 1988 (Box 004)
    - FUNKHOUSER, CHRISTOPHER, -3 letters 1994 - 1995 (Box 004)
    - GANICK, PETER, - 3 letters and 3 postcards 1987 - 1991 (Box 004)
    - GELPI, ALBERT, -1 letter 1981 (Box 004)
    - GLOVER, ALBERT, - 7 letters and 2 postcards 1987 - 1998 (Box 004)
    - HARDING, GUNNAR, - 5 letters and 1 postcard 1988 - 1989 (Box 004)
    - HARRIS, MARK, - 2 letters 1960 - 1977 - 3 letters, RG to MH (originals) 1960 (Box 004)
    - HARTLEY, GEORGE, - 1 postcard 1986 (Box 004)
    - HEJINIAN, LYN, - 5 letters 1983 - 1988 -2 letters, RG to LH (xerox) 1988 (Box 004)
    - HOCQUARD, EMMANUEL, - 3 letters 1981 - 1985 (Box 004)
    - HOLLO, ANSELM, - 14 letters and 6 postcards 1976 - 1997 - 1 letter, RG to AH (xerox) 1988 (Box 004)
    - IRBY, KENNETH, - approx. 181 letters and 32 postcards 1963 - 1998 - 1 letter, RG to KI (xerox) 1989 (Box 007)
    - KEYES, ROGER, - 10 letters and 4 postcards 1960 - 1997 -1 letter, RG to RK 1988 (Box 008)
    - KYGER, JOANNE, - 3 letters and 15 postcards 1972 - 1998 (Box 008)
    - LANSING, GERRIT, - 1 letter 1994 (Box 008)
    - LAUGHLIN, JAMES, - 1 letter 1985 (Box 008)
    - LAWTHER, MARCIA, - 15 letters and 5 postcards 1972 - 1990 (Box 008)
    - LORD, EMILY, -EL/RG Xmas card 1965 - 1 letter, RG to EL 1962 (Box 008)
    - MACADAMS, LEWIS, - 1 letter and 1 postcard 1971 - 1976 (Box 008)
    - MAYER, BERNADETTE, - 1 letter and 1 postcard 1983 - 1984 (Box 008)
    - MCCARTHY, EUGENE, - 1 letter 1959 (Box 008)
    - MCCLURE, MICHAEL, - 1 postcard 1993 (Box 008)
    - MCCOLLOM, MARION, - 3 letters 1976 - 1983 (Box 008)
    - MCNAUGHTON, DUNCAN, - 6 letters and 2 postcards 1987 - 1998 (Box 008)
    - MILES, JOSEPHINE, - 1 letter and 1 postcard 1970 - 1971 (Box 008)
    - MORIARTY, LAURA, - 1 letter 1985 (Box 008)
    - MORICE, DAVE, - 1 letter 1971 (Box 008)
    - NELSON-RANEY, STEVE, - 9 letters, various cards and musical scores 1988 - 1997 (Box 008)
    - NOTLEY, ALICE, - 5 letters and 1 postcard 1984 - 1990 (Box 008)
    - OLSON, CHARLES, - 1 letter 1963 (Box 008)
    - PATULLO, EDWARD, - 1 letter 1960 (Box 008)
    - PAUL, SHERMAN, - 1 letter 1975 (Box 008)
    - PERELMAN, BOB, - 13 letters and 1 postcard 1972 - 1990 - 2 postcards from Francie Shaw to RG 1976 - 1977 (Box 008)
    - PETTET, SIMON, - 1 letter and 8 postcards 1987 - 1997 (Box 008)
    - QUAN, SALLIE, - 4 letters w/ "rhymms" pictures of RG, SQ and Amy Grenier 1977 - 1979 (Box 008)
    - QUARTERMAIN, PETER, - 1 letter 1989 (Box 008)
    - RANDALL, JAMES, - 1 letter 1966 (Box 008)
    - RASULA, JED, -3 letters and 3 postcards 1984 - 1990 (Box 008)
    - RATCLIFFE, STEPHEN, - 3 letters and 1 postcard 1987 - 1998 (Box 008)
    - RAWORTH, TOM, - 11 letters and 3 postcards 1981 - 1995 -1 letter, RG to TR (xerox) 1991 (Box 008)
    - REXROTH, MARIE, - 7 letters 1964 - 1980 (Box 008)
    - ROBINSON, KIT, - 2 letters 1977 - 1990 (Box 008)
    - RODEFER, STEPHEN, - 1 letter 1984 - 1 letter, RG to SR 1984 (Box 008)
    - SCALAPINO, LESLIE, - 2 letters and 1 postcard 1984 - 1994 (Box 008)
    - SCHELLING, ANDREW, - 2 postcards 1990 - 1991 (Box 008)
    - SHEEHAN, DON, - 7 letters 1976 - 1994 (Box 008)
    - SHERRY, JAMES, - 3 letters and 2 postcards 1978 - 1986 (Box 008)
    - SILLIMAN, RON, - 20 letters and 5 postcards 1970 - 1992 (Box 008)
    - SMITH, CHARLES, - 1 letter 1987 (Box 008)
    - STARBUCK, GEORGE, - 2 letters 1977 (Box 008)
    - TILLICH, PAUL, - 1 letter 1960 (Box 008)
    - TILLINGHAST, RICHARD, - 2 letters 1967 - 1989 (Box 008)
    - WARSHALL, PETER, - 7 letters 1968 - 1974 (Box 008)
    - WATTEN, BARRETT, - 43 letters and 7 postcards 1970 - 1981 (Box 008)
    - WESSNER, LAURA, - 13 letter and 11 postcards 1973 - 1997 - 2 birthday cards to RG - 1 book of poems 1975 (Box 008)
    - WILL, FREDERIC, - 4 letters and 1 postcard 1968 - 1994 (Box 008)
    - ZUKOFSKY, LOUIS, - 3 postcards 1972 - 1974 (Box 008)
  - Family Correspondence
    - A. Parents
      - 1. Beatrice Olivia (Bjeldanes) Grenier (Mother) to RG 1952 - 1974, - 41 letters - 1 postcard (Box 006)
      - 2. Judson Achille Grenier (Father) to RG 1965 - 1976, - 7 letters (Box 006)
      - 3. RG to Parents 1959 - 1974, - 105 letters - 1 postcard (Box 006)
    - B. Bjeldanes Aunts
      - 1. Augusta Bjeldanes to RG 1948 - 1980, - 6 letters - 39 postcards (Box 006)
      - 2. Ragnhild Bjeldanes to RG 1967 - 1991, - 27 letters - 7 postcards (Box 006)
      - 3. Ragnhild Bjeldanes to relatives generally 1966 - 1978, - 19 letters (Box 006)
      - 4. RG to Bjeldanes Aunts 1959 - 1982, - 17 letters (Box 006)
    - B. Brother/Sister-in-Law
      - 1. Judson A. Grenier, Jr. and Nancy Hicks Grenier to RG 1963 - 1998, - 22 letters - 1 postcard (Box 006)
      - 2. RG to Judd and Nancy 1959 - 1969, - 11 letters - 32 poems (RG original ts.) (Box 006)
    - D. Daughter
      - 1. Amy Eliza Grenier to RG 1976 - 1987, - 2 letters - 4 postcards - 1 birthday card (w/"rhymms" photo of Amy) (Box 006)
- Series III. Others' Manuscripts 1950 - 1999, Alphabetized by author, dated/ chronologized and counted (by pages of text) in folders. Contained in 3½ boxes.
  - A. Manuscripts of Original Work Sent RG for Review and Comment
    - 1. KATHI AGUERO Materials, (18 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Poems from RG's Poetry Writing class at Tufts University, 1970-1971, (KA tss.)
    - 2. STEVE BENSON Materials, (33 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - SB ts. of review of OCKER by P. Inman (Tuumba Press, 1982), (xerox)
      - Xerox of SB's BRIARCOMBE PARAGRAPHS (Moving Letters Press, 1984) inscribed for RG, November 1989
      - Xerox of SB note "ON TIME" n.d., signed
    - 3. CHARLES BERNSTEIN Materials, (58 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - CB holograph letter to RG, 1983 Mar 31, enclosing
      - CB ts. of CB & Susan B. Laufer's essay "MEANING THE MEANING: ARAKAWA'S CRITIQUE OF SPACE", (xerox)
        Pub.in CB.'s Content's Dream (Sun & Moon Press, 1986)
      - CB ts. of CB's essay "FRAMES OF REFERENCE", (xerox)
        Published in CB's Content's Dream (Sun & Moon, 1986)
      - Page proofs of CB's essay "WORDS AND PICTURES" with CB holograph corrections, (xerox)
        Pub. in CB's Content's Dream (Sun & Moon, 1986)
      - Two pp. from CB ts. of CB talk "CHARACTERIZATION", (xerox)
        Delivered at 80 Langton Street in San Francisco in January 1983, containing exchange w/ RG re irony in CB's work, pub. in CB's Content's Dream (Sun & Moon, 1986)
    - 4. JIM BRODEY Materials, (2 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - JB original holograph poem "Poem" signed & inscribed for RG 1989 July 16
        (discovered by RG February 1999, possibly only copy)
      - Joanne Kyger memorial page for JB w/ JB poem "AT PEACE", 1942 Nov 30 - 1993 July 16, (xerox)
        Part of September 2, 1993 ceremony in which JK, RG, Bill Berkson & Bill Beckman scattered JB's ashes into Pacific at Agate Beach, Bolinas
    - 5. DAVID BROMIGE Materials, (485 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - DB ts. of DB prose piece "SECRET SUBORNERS" from ca. early 1980's, (xerox)
        w/ DB & RG holograph changes
      - DB ts. of first four chapters of DB novel THEY ATE from the early 1980's, (xerox)
        Pub. by X Press (1992)
      - DB ts. of DB prose piece "JOY CONE"
        Pub. in Hills, No. 9 (1981)
      - DB ts./holograph of DB collage piece "NOTES / part one" from the early 1980's, (xerox)
      - Announcement of DB three-day residency at New Langton Arts in San Francisco entitled "HOW TO TALK ABOUT IMPORTANT MATTERS", ca. 1982 July 10, 12 & 14
      - DB ts. of "Voices Seeking You", collaboration by DB & Steve Benson beginning "You're looking for something to do...", from ca. 1982
        Pub. in Interruptions (1994)
      - DB ts. of DB's "A NOTE ON TJANTING", pub. in Ron Silliman issue of The Difficulties, No. 2 1985, (xerox)
      - DB ts. of course notes for DB's Introduction to Poetry at Sonoma State University, beginning "The essence of poetry is rime...", (xerox) w/ DB holograph comment
      - DB exchange w/ Bob Perelman re DB's essay/notes "UNSUBJECTED WRITING":
        - DB letter to RG, 1985 Mar 13, (ts. w/ holograph additions) enclosing
        - DB ts. of "UNSUBJECTED WRITING", (xerox)
        - BP letter to DB re same, 1983 July 23, (xerox)
        - DB response to BP letter, 1983 Aug 7, (xerox)
      - DB ts. of DB poem "AMERICAN TESTAMENT" n.d., (xerox) w/DB holograph notes to RG
        Pub. in The Difficulties, No. 3 (1987)
      - DB ts. of DB poem "COLLABORATIONS / (Part Three of AMERICAN TESTAMENT) " n.d., (xerox)
      - DB ts. of DB poem "MY DADDY'S AT HIS OFFICE NOW / (Part Four of AMERICAN TESTAMENT)" n.d., (xerox)
      - DB tss. of DB poems from the mid-1980's:
        - "Maintenance of membership", (xerox)
        - "A Marriage", (xerox)
        - "The Name Tag", (xerox)
        - "Writer's Lamp", (xerox)
        - "O.K.", (xerox)
        - "Two fer Bob"
        - "Can't You Decline This?", (xerox)
        - "What to Call it", (xerox)
        - "Glib", (xerox)
        - "Wine glass"
        - "Scum", (xerox)
        - "The Holy Bible", (xerox)
        - "A Sense of Humor's Soliloquy", (xerox)
        - "Plaint, n.", (xerox)
        - "The Idea and The Actuality", (xerox)
        - "joseph conrad", (xerox)
        - "it was hard when she left", (xerox)
        - "You See", (xerox)
          Pub. by e.g. editions, 1986
      - DB ts. of DB poem "It's the Same Only Different", (xerox)
        Pub. in DB's Desire (Black Sparrow, 1988)
      - DB holograph notes to/revisions of RG ts. of RG poem "LAND", (xerox)
        Pub. in RG's Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986)
      - DB ts. of DB prose piece "WHEN I CLOSED MY EYES, I SAW WHAT BOB GRENIER SAW WHEN HE OPENED HIS: THE CLOSE OF UNE SEMAINE DE BONTE BY MAX ERNST" dated 1986 Apr 2, (xerox)
        Pub. in DB's Men, Women & Vehicles (Black Sparrow, 1990)
      - DB anthology for DB's English 470 at Sonoma State, "SOME CALIFORNIA POETS" w/ poems by RG
      - DB ts. of DB poem "In an orchard, in August", w/ DB holograph revisions
        Inscribed for RG, pub. in DB's Desire (Black Sparrow, 1988)
      - DB ts. of "DAVID BROMIGE INTERVIEWED BY STEPHEN RATCLIFFE, FOR THE POETRY CENTER, SF STATE UNIVERSITY, "1987 APR 30, (xerox) w/ DB holograph changes
      - DB ts. of DB biography of Susan Howe from ca. 1987, (xerox)
        Pub. in Magill's Literary Encyclopedia
      - DB account of Samuel Beckett's Malone Dies n.d.
        (xerox from Magill's Literary Encyclopedia)
      - DB broadside of DB poem "THE MAD CAREER" from 1989
        Pub. as A Twybl Broadside
      - DB holograph note to RG, 1990 Aug 12
        Enclosing xerox of two poems from Sulfur (1989?), "BY DRAWING A LINE" & "A SET OF TWELVE"
      - DB ts. of DB poem sequence "A SET OF TWELVE", (xerox)
        Pub. in DB's The Harbormaster of Hong Kong (Sun & Moon Press, 1993)
      - DB ts. of DB's poem sequence "3-5 poems of friendship", (xerox)
        Pub. in DB's The Harbormaster of Hong Kong (Sun & Moon, 1993)
      - DB ts. of DB poem sequence "While knitting", (xerox)
        Pub. in DB's A CAST OF TENS (Avec Books, 1994)
      - DB print-out of DB poem sequence "pages from the american event", (xerox)
        Some of which were pub. in DB's The Harbormaster of Hong Kong (Sun & Moon, 1993)
      - Five student responses to poetry reading by RG at Sonoma State U. in 1992 May
        Written for DB's class
      - DB holograph letter to RG, 1993 Jan 29
        Enclosing DB print-outs of poems to be included in A CAST OF TENS (Avec, 1994), "Of Billions" & "To--"
      - DB print-out of DB poem "& MOON" inscribed for RG 1994 July
        Pub. in 50: A Celebration of Sun & Moon Classics, ed. Douglas Messerli (Sun & Moon, 1995)
      - Xerox of "BOTH", a collaborative poem begun in1997
        By DB, RG & Cecelia Belle Bromige (DB's wife) (unfinished).
      - Xerox of DB's "David Mansfield Bromige"
        From Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series, Vol. 26 (Gale Research, 1997) w/ photo of DB & RG
      - Xerox of "David Bromige" by Charla Howard, in Dictionary of Literary Biography, Vol. 193 (Gale Research, 1998
      - DB print-out of DB poem "Unreached by Version" ca. 1998, w/DB holograph note.
      - DB print-out of DB poem "T as in Tethered" from ca. 1998
        To be pub. in DB's book As In T As In Tethered (Chax Press, 2002) w/ introduction by RG
    - 6. AVERY E.D. BURNS Materials, (14 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - A.E.D.B. holograph letter to RG, 1995 Nov 20, enclosing
      - A.E.D.B. print-out of A.E.D.B.'s Idler Wheel
    - 7. TOM CLARK Materials, (ca. 76 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - TC broadside poem "Back In Tulsa" n.d.
        Pub. by The Alternative Press
      - Collection of documents entitled "MINOR MOMENTS IN THE GREAT LANGUAGE POETRY WARS" (1985 Summer ):
        - TC article in Poetry Flash "Stalin As Linguist" (No. 148, 1985 July)
        - Xerox of RG holograph letter to TC responding to TC's "Stalin As Linguist" (1985 July 4 )
        - "FLASHBACK" section of Poetry Flash w/ various responses to TC article (No. 149, 1985 Aug )
        - "FLASHBACK" section of Poetry Flash w/ further responses to article (No. 150, 1985 Sept )
      - RG exchange w/ Ron Silliman re TC article:
        - RS ts. letter to RG, 1985 July 30
        - RG holograph letter to RS, 1985 Aug 4, (xerox)
        - RS holograph postcard to RG, 1985 Aug 6
        - RG holograph letter to RS, 1985 Aug 11, (xerox)
      - RG exchange w/ Tom Beckett re book of interviews TB had proposed (which never appeared):
        - TB ts. letter to RG, 1985 June 23
        - TB ts. postcard to RG, 1985 July 28
        - RG holograph letter to Barrett Watten, 1985 Aug 9, (xerox)
        - RG holograph letter to TB, 1985 Aug 12, (xerox)
      - Gary Kamiya article in The Berkeley Monthly "CAN ALL THE NEW POETS PUT THE WORDS BACK TOGETHER AGAIN?" 1986 Dec
      - TC holograph poem card, "FOR BOB GRENIER", signed ca. 1986
      - TC postcard to RG re RG's WHAT I BELIEVE TRANSPIRATION/TRANSPIRING MINNESOTA (0 Books, 1991), holograph (1991)
    - 8. JOHN CLARKE Materials, (ca. 244 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Duncan McNaughton ts. letter to RG, 1986 Apr 28
      - DM holograph letter to RG, 1986 May 5, enclosing
      - Xerox of second galley proofs of John Clarke's From Feathers To Iron (Tombouctou/Convivio, 1987)
    - 9. ROBERT CREELEY Materials, (10 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Xerox of holograph 70th birthday poem for RC, "HAPPY Birthday BOB Creeley!", 1996 May 21
        By Joanne Kyger, Stephen Ratcliffe, Diana Middleton-McQuaid, Steve Tills & RG (from Bolinas)
      - Xerox of what appears to be RC course materials, "NOTES ON POETRY: I"
        w/ unknown person's drawing of RC (from SUNY/Buffalo? when?)
    - 10. MICHAEL DAVIDSON Materials, (31 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - MD ts. of MD essay "Archaeologist of Morning: Charles Olson, Edward Dorn and Historical Method" from ca. 1979, (xerox)
    - 11. LARRY EIGNER Materials, (ca. 165 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - LE's copy of Jack Collom's magazine, the 6 (1960)
        Contains LE holograph poem inscribed at inserted sheet ("cave/plowing/flying/head/tongue/space/upon time//// throats"--pub. in the 7)
      - RG 'established texts' of LE poems (typed 1970 - 1971), 63 pp. (xeroxes)
        (need to be checked against LE archive material--'new' poems here?)
      - Letters to LE by various hands (Barrett Watten, Douglas Woolf, Ron Silliman), mid -1970's
      - Two signed copies of LE broadside poem beginning, "no radio/bag/over a shoulder.. ." (Lodestar Press, 1974)
      - Two original LE tss. from 1975 Nov("once worlds were..." & "If he cut the/definite article" pub. in Hills No. 4 (1977 May)
      - Various xeroxes of LE poems from 1970's
      - Xerox of LE book suddenly it gets light and dark in the street (Green Horse Booklet, No. 8, 1975)
      - Materials relating to publication of Waters/Places/A Time by LE (ed. RG) (Black Sparrow, 1983):
        - Letter from John Martin to RG, 1980 May 12
        - Letter from John Martin to RG, 1982 Jan 22
        - Letter from Linda Press to RG, 1982 Nov 1
        - Two Drafts by LE (original tss.) toward "Biography"
        - RG ts. of final "Biography" note
        - RG ts. of list of previous books by LE
      - Xerox of LE ts. response to St. Mark's Poetry Project Newsletter's Questionnaire, 1989 Sept
      - Xerox of Crag Hill's (Score?) review of LE's areas/lights/heights (Writings 1954 - 1989)
        Ed. Benjamin Friedlander (Roof Books, 1989)
      - Two copies of LE 'poetcard' w/ poem "0 Jerusalem" (Poltroon Press, 1992)
      - Somebody's (whose?) perceptive notes on LE's method
      - Michael McClure poem "february morning" for LE, 1996 Feb 5